food.gov.uk 2019-04-09

# Privacy policy | Food Standards Agency

## How we handle your personal data

The Food Standards Agency is what is known as the ‘Controller’ of the personal data we collect from you or which is provided to us.

When we collect your personal information, we will:

  * make sure you know why we need it and why we are legally allowed to hold it
  * only ask for what we need, and not to collect too much or irrelevant information
  * protect it and make sure nobody has access to it who shouldn’t
  * let you know if we share it with other organisations
  * make sure we don’t keep it longer than necessary

All the personal data we process is located on servers within the European union. Our cloud based services have been procured through the government framework agreements and these services have been assessed against the national cyber security centre cloud security principles.

### Visitors to our websites

This privacy statement only covers Food Standards Agency websites. It does not cover links within our sites to other websites.

The system will record your email address and other information if volunteered to us by you. This shall be treated as proprietary and confidential. It may be used for internal review and to notify you about updates to our websites.

## Your rights

You have a right to see the information we hold on you by making a request in writing to the email address below. If at any point you believe the information we process on you is incorrect you can request to have it corrected. If you wish to raise a complaint on how we have handled your personal data, you can contact our Data Protection Officer who will investigate the matter.

If you are not satisfied with our response or believe we are processing your personal data not in accordance with the law you can complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO).

Our Data Protection Officer in the FSA is the Information Management and Security Team Leader who can be contacted at [informationmanagement@food.gov.uk](mailto:informationmanagement@food.gov.uk)

## Privacy notices

We provide privacy notices for the following services:

  * Advisory Committee on Animal Feedingstuffs")

  * Advisory Committee on the Microbiological Safety of Foods

  * [Animal feed, TSES and animal by-products legislation and policy](https://food.gov.uk/other/privacy-notice-for-animal-feed-tses-or-animal-by-products-legislation-and-policy)
  * [Annual surveillance to monitor levels of acrylamide and furans](https://www.food.gov.uk/about-us/privacy-notice-monitoring-levels-of-acrylamide-and-furans)
  * Advisory Committee for Social Science
  * Board Members
  * Campylobacter retail survey
  * Committee on Toxicity (COT)")
  * [Correspondence regarding policies on food and feed hygiene, safety and standards](https://www.food.gov.uk/about-us/privacy-notice-for-correspondence-regarding-policies-on-food-and-feed-hygiene-safety-and-standards)
  * Exception reports for Approved Assurance Schemes
  * External complaints against the FSA
  * Food contact materials
  * Freedom of Information requests

  * Health, Safety and Wellbeing Unit

  * HR staff data

  * [Invitation and circulation of information about FSA board meetings](https://www.food.gov.uk/about-us/privacy-notice-invitations-and-circulation-of-information-about-fsa-board-meetings)

  * Job application and pre-employment screening data

  * Local authority contacts

  * MyHACCP

  * Northern Ireland Food Advisory Committee

  * Novel foods and GM foods policy

  * News and alerts subscription service

  * National Food Crime Unit

  * Notification of a prohibited person database

  * [Ongoing information received from individuals as part of the Consultation on the EU Review of Official Controls](https://www.food.gov.uk/about-us/privacy-notice-for-ongoing-information-received-from-individuals-as-part-of-the-consultation-on-the-eu-review-of-official)

  * Policy development records for meat hygiene
  * Procurement tenders
  * Procurement contracts
  * Regulating Our Future Newsletter
  * Registering as a milk production holding
  * Register a food business
  * Register a food business support service for local authorities
  * Records from GM research programmes
  * Reporting a food problem
  * Stakeholder contact information in Northern Ireland
  * Stakeholder contact information
  * Shellfish sanitary survey data
  * [Temporary Certificate of Competence and Certificate of Competence](https://www.food.gov.uk/about-us/privacy-notice-temporary-certificate-of-competence-and-certificate-of-competence)
  * UK Wine Producers
  * Welsh Food Advisory Committee
  * Welsh language services

## Cookies

When we provide services, we want to make them easy, useful and reliable. food.gov.uk puts small files (known as ‘cookies’) onto your computer to collect information about how you browse the site. Find out how we use cookies and how you can control them.
